export const quizzes = [
 {
    title: "English",
    questions: [
      { question: "1. ____ you interested in sport?", options: ["Be", "Am", "Is", "Are"], answer: "Are" },
      { question: "2. My ___ is a writer and his books are very popular.", options: ["Aunt", "Uncle", "Sister", "Mother"], answer: "Uncle" },
      { question: "3. We live in the city center and our house ____ have a big garden", options: ["does not", "isn’t", "aren’t", "don’t"], answer: "does not" },
      { question: "4. There ___ a lot of people outside the school. What's the problem?", options: ["are", "is", "be", "am"], answer: "are" },
      { question: "5. Cathy ____ a game on her computer at the moment.", options: ["plays", "is playing", "to play", "play"], answer: "is playing" },
      { question: "6. Paul is very ____. He doesn't like to take any photos of himself.", options: ["bored", "confident", "angry", "shy"], answer: "shy" },
      { question: "7. ____ you like to come out with us tonight?", options: ["Do", "Would", "Are", "Will"], answer: "Would" },
      { question: "8. Dad's ___ work right now. He's a teacher.", options: ["on", "at", "for", "by"], answer: "at" },
      { question: "9. Did you ___ shopping after school yesterday?", options: ["went", "goed", "going", "go"], answer: "go" },
      { question: "10. There wasn't ___ milk for breakfast this morning so I had toast and orange juice.", options: ["a", "some", "the", "any"], answer: "any" },
      { question: "11. I ___ five emails before school today.", options: ["sent", "sended", "did send", "was send"], answer: "sent" },
      { question: "12. Turn ___ and you'll see the museum on the left.", options: ["on the right", "the right", "by the right", "right"], answer: "right" },
      { question: "13. The beach was very crowded ___ Monday.", options: ["in", "on", "at", "to"], answer: "on" },
      { question: "14. I __ the new Batman film yet. Is it any good?", options: ["have not seen", "didn’t see", "don’t", "am not seen"], answer: "have not seen" },
      { question: "15. Tom got the ___ marks in the class for his homework.", options: ["worse", "worst", "baddest", "most bad"], answer: "worst" },
      { question: "16. You ___ eat all that cake! It isn't good for you.", options: ["don’t", "my not", "should not", "will not"], answer: "should not" },
      { question: "17. How ___ time have we got to do this exercise?", options: ["long", "many", "much", "quick"], answer: "much" },
      { question: "18. Don't forget to get ___ the bus at Station Road.", options: ["off", "many", "much", "quick"], answer: "off" },
      { question: "19. Our teacher speaks English to us ___ so that we can understand her.", options: ["slow", "slower", "more slowlier", "slowly"], answer: "slowly" },
      { question: "20. My sister ___ speak French when she was only six years old.", options: ["was", "could", "should", "had"], answer: "could" },
      { question: "21. I really enjoy ___ new languages and I'd like to learn Italian soon.", options: ["a to learn", "learning", "learn", "learned"], answer: "learning" },
      { question: "22. My father has been a pilot ___ twenty years and he still loves his job.", options: ["since", "for", "until", "by"], answer: "for" },
      { question: "23. Be quick - get the food inside! It ___.", options: ["rains", "is raining", "start rain", "can rain"], answer: "is raining" },
      { question: "24. Sam asked me if I ___ a lift home after the concert.", options: ["have wanted", "wanted", "would want", "want"], answer: "wanted" },
      { question: "25. Which train ___ for when I saw you on the platform on Sunday?", options: ["did you wait", "were you waiting", "have you waited", "are you waiting"], answer: "were you waiting" },
      { question: "26. I ___ not be home this evening. Phone me on my mobile.", options: ["can", "could", "may", "should"], answer: "may" },
      { question: "27. I hope you ___ a good time at the moment in Greece! Phone soon.", options: ["are having", "have", "have had", "had"], answer: "are having" },
      { question: "28. If we ___ in the countryside, we'd have much better views than we do now.", options: ["lived", "were live", "would live", "lives"], answer: "lived" },
      { question: "29. Do students in your country have to stand ___ when the teacher arrives?", options: ["on", "at", "in", "up"], answer: "up" },
      { question: "30. You ___ hurry as we've still got twenty minutes before the film starts.", options: ["mustn’t", "can’t", "may not", "need not to"], answer: "need not to" },
      { question: "31. I wanted to see Harry. How long ago ___?", options: ["he left", "has he left", "did he leave", "could he leave"], answer: "did he leave" },
      { question: "32. I wish Joe ___ to Hawaii on holiday. They're talking about an eruption there on the news.", options: ["doesn’t go", "didn’t went", "has not gone", "had not gone"], answer: "had not gone" },
      { question: "33. Could I possibly ____ some money for the bus fare home? I've lost my bag.", options: ["lend", "owe", "borrow", "need"], answer: "borrow" },
      { question: "34. People say that an avalanche ___ by loud noises in the area but I don't know if that's true.", options: ["causes", "has caused", "is causing", "is caused"], answer: "is caused" },
      { question: "35. You'll have to drive much ___ than this if you want to pass your test.", options: ["carefuller", "more careful", "more carefully", "careful"], answer: "more carefully" },
      { question: "36. I must remember ___ Ed to take notes for me while I'm away next week.", options: ["ask", "to ask", "to asking", "for ask"], answer: "to ask" },
      { question: "37. Look at the news! Three cars ___ in a bad accident on the motorway at Dartford recently.", options: ["are involving", "involve", "have involved", "have been involved"], answer: "have been involved" },
      { question: "38. I ___ for arriving so late but I was caught up in a traffic jam in the town centre.", options: ["sorry", "regret", "apologize", "afraid"], answer: "apologize" },
      { question: "39. It was great to see you at the party. I didn't realize how long ___ since we last met.", options: ["it had been", "it was been", "it was being", "it is been"], answer: "it had been" },
      { question: "40. I'm sorry to trouble you but I was wondering what …", options: ["time it is", "time was it", "is the time", "time is it"], answer: "time it is" },
      { question: "41. I really wish people ___ dump litter in front of our house. We have to clean it up every day.", options: ["will not", "would not", "have not", "do not"], answer: "would not" },
      { question: "42. Last Tuesday the company told Ruth that they'd emailed her the job details the ___ day.", options: ["last", "before", "previous", "earlier"], answer: "previous" },
      { question: "43. The studio lights went out while the footballer ___.", options: ["had been", "was interviewed", "was being interviewed", "was interviewing"], answer: "was being interviewed" },
      { question: "44. By the time I hand in this project, I ____ on it for three weeks!", options: ["‘ll be working", "‘ll have been working", "‘ll have worked", "‘ll work"], answer: "‘ll have been working" },
      { question: "45. Jonah's just fallen down the steps outside, got bad injury and there's ___ everywhere.", options: ["bone", "blood", "skin", "cut"], answer: "blood" },
      { question: "46. You should be very proud ___ what you've achieved over the last year.", options: ["of", "on", "to", "for"], answer: "of" },
      { question: "47. ___ people know this but our school is being inspected today.", options: ["few", "little", "any", "none"], answer: "few" },
      { question: "48. Look out for a petrol station because I think we're going to run ___ of petrol soon.", options: ["down", "out", "off", "through"], answer: "out" },
      { question: "49. If I hadn’t gone off bazaar yesterday, I ___ one of those cheap bags.", options: ["could have bought", "had bought", "would buy", "bought"], answer: "could have bought" },
      { question: "50. Come on, kids! Aren't you__ yet? Breakfast's on the table.", options: ["in", "on", "up", "off"], answer: "in" }
    ]
  },
  {
    title: "Russian",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "1. Как переводится слово 'Hello'?", 
        options: ["Привет", "Пока", "Спасибо", "Пожалуйста"], 
        answer: "Привет"
      },
      {
        question: "2. Как сказать 'Спасибо' по-русски?", 
        options: ["Hello", "Thanks", "Спасибо", "Пока"], 
        answer: "Спасибо"
      },
      {
        question: "3. Выберите правильный артикль: ___ книга на столе.", 
        options: ["A", "An", "The", "No article"], 
        answer: "The"
      },
      {
        question: "4. Как переводится 'Dog'?", 
        options: ["Кот", "Собака", "Птица", "Лошадь"], 
        answer: "Собака"
      },
      {
        question: "5. Выберите правильный вариант: Я ___ студент.", 
        options: ["am", "is", "are", "be"], 
        answer: "am"
      },
      {
        question: "6. Как сказать 'Я люблю читать книги'?", 
        options: ["I read books", "I love to read books", "I reading books", "I books read"], 
        answer: "I love to read books"
      },
      {
        question: "7. Выберите правильное слово: Она ___ врач.", 
        options: ["is", "am", "are", "be"], 
        answer: "is"
      },
      {
        question: "8. Как переводится 'Good morning'?", 
        options: ["Добрый вечер", "Доброе утро", "Спокойной ночи", "Привет"], 
        answer: "Доброе утро"
      },
      {
        question: "9. Выберите правильное продолжение: Мы ___ идем в школу.", 
        options: ["is", "am", "are", "be"], 
        answer: "are"
      },
      {
        question: "10. Как переводится 'Cat'?", 
        options: ["Собака", "Кот", "Птица", "Рыба"], 
        answer: "Кот"
      },
      {
        question: "11. Выберите правильное слово: Я ___ из России.", 
        options: ["am", "is", "are", "be"], 
        answer: "am"
      },
      {
        question: "12. Как сказать 'I like apples' по-русски?", 
        options: ["Я люблю яблоки", "Я люблю груши", "Я хочу яблоки", "Мне яблоки"], 
        answer: "Я люблю яблоки"
      },
      {
        question: "13. Выберите правильный вариант: Они ___ дома.", 
        options: ["is", "are", "am", "be"], 
        answer: "are"
      },
      {
        question: "14. Как переводится 'Thank you very much'?", 
        options: ["Большое спасибо", "Пожалуйста", "Извини", "Привет"], 
        answer: "Большое спасибо"
      },
      {
        question: "15. Выберите правильное слово: Он ___ мой друг.", 
        options: ["is", "am", "are", "be"], 
        answer: "is"
      },
      {
        question: "16. Как сказать 'I don’t understand'?", 
        options: ["Я понимаю", "Я не понимаю", "Я понял", "Я учусь"], 
        answer: "Я не понимаю"
      },
      {
        question: "17. Выберите правильный вариант: Ты ___ из Китая?", 
        options: ["is", "are", "am", "be"], 
        answer: "are"
      },
      {
        question: "18. Как переводится 'Good night'?", 
        options: ["Доброй ночи", "Добрый день", "Доброе утро", "Привет"], 
        answer: "Доброй ночи"
      },
      {
        question: "19. Выберите правильное слово: Я ___ читать.", 
        options: ["like", "likes", "liking", "liked"], 
        answer: "like"
      },
      {
        question: "20. Как сказать 'See you later' по-русски?", 
        options: ["Увидимся позже", "Привет", "До завтра", "Пока"], 
        answer: "Увидимся позже"
      },
      {
        question: "21. Выберите правильный вариант: Мы ___ друзья.", 
        options: ["is", "are", "am", "be"], 
        answer: "are"
      },
      {
        question: "22. Как переводится 'Please'?", 
        options: ["Пожалуйста", "Спасибо", "Извини", "Привет"], 
        answer: "Пожалуйста"
      },
      {
        question: "23. Выберите правильный вариант: Она ___ учительница.", 
        options: ["is", "am", "are", "be"], 
        answer: "is"
      },
      {
        question: "24. Как сказать 'I am happy'?", 
        options: ["Я счастлив", "Я грустный", "Мне весело", "Я рад"], 
        answer: "Я рад"
      },
      {
        question: "25. Выберите правильное слово: Они ___ дома.", 
        options: ["is", "are", "am", "be"], 
        answer: "are"
      },
      {
        question: "26. Как переводится 'Excuse me'?", 
        options: ["Извините", "Спасибо", "Привет", "Пока"], 
        answer: "Извините"
      },
      {
        question: "27. Выберите правильный вариант: Я ___ студент.", 
        options: ["am", "is", "are", "be"], 
        answer: "am"
      },
      {
        question: "28. Как сказать 'I am tired'?", 
        options: ["Я устал", "Я счастлив", "Мне весело", "Я голоден"], 
        answer: "Я устал"
      },
      {
        question: "29. Выберите правильное слово: Он ___ врач.", 
        options: ["is", "am", "are", "be"], 
        answer: "is"
      },
      {
        question: "30. Как перевести 'Goodbye'?", 
        options: ["Привет", "Пока", "Спасибо", "Извини"], 
        answer: "Пока"
      }
    ]
  },
];
